<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>matt9j:Matt Johnson</title>
    <link>https://matt9j.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on matt9j:Matt Johnson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matt9j.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Green Bean Casserole</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/green-bean-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/green-bean-casserole/</guid>
      <description>I love green bean casserole, a lot. Unfortunatley most &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; recipes require the use of canned condensed mushroom soup, which almost always has soy! I discovered this recipe for a version based on cheese instead, and have enjoyed it!
Instructions  Preheat the oven to 350F Melt butter into a large skillet (medium heat) Add flower and stir until it forms a smooth paste Quickly add green beans, sour cream, salt, and sugar&amp;ndash; don&amp;rsquo;t let the flower paste get overcooked/burned!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Asyncronous iperf3 Tests in Android 11&#43;</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/posts/integrating-iperf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/posts/integrating-iperf/</guid>
      <description>Preamble I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping out the Seattle Community Network (SCN), with an ongoing project to build a crowdsourced network performance measurement application for Android. While understanding modern network performance, particularly wireless networks, is extremely subtle, &amp;ldquo;speedtests&amp;rdquo; offer a crude yet popular way to measure a network&amp;rsquo;s performance, and are easy for general audiences to interpret.
Unsurprisingly, SCN sought to include a &amp;ldquo;speedtest&amp;rdquo; capability in their app! A team of volunteer undergraduate researchers (Zhennan(John) Zhou &amp;amp; Ashwin Chintalapati) organized by Esther Jang got started on the project, and started integrating iperf3 (C, BSD-3 into the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building iperf3 For Android 11&#43;</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/posts/building-iperf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/posts/building-iperf/</guid>
      <description>Preamble I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping out the Seattle Community Network (SCN), with an ongoing project to build a crowdsourced network performance measurement application for Android. While understanding modern network performance, particularly wireless networks, is extremely subtle, &amp;ldquo;speedtests&amp;rdquo; offer a crude yet popular way to measure a network&amp;rsquo;s performance, and are easy for general audiences to interpret.
Unsurprisingly, SCN sought to include a &amp;ldquo;speedtest&amp;rdquo; capability in their app! A team of volunteer undergraduate researchers (Zhennan(John) Zhou &amp;amp; Ashwin Chintalapati) organized by Esther Jang got started on the project, and started integrating iperf3 (C, BSD-3 into the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Capacity as Common Pool Resource: Community-Based Congestion Management in a Community Network</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/cscw21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/cscw21/</guid>
      <description>abstract: Congestion control mechanisms, by which network users share constrained capacity on Internet links, are heavily studied in computer science. Such mechanisms are traditionally automated, assuming that users do not wish to be involved in addressing congestion. However, in community-owned and operated networks, users have control over daily operational choices. We explore the design of community-based congestion policies and mechanisms, through the lens of network capacity as a Common Pool Resource (CPR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whale Watching in Inland Indonesia: Analyzing a Small, Remote, Internet-Based Community Cellular Network</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/www21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/www21/</guid>
      <description>abstract: While only generating a minuscule percentage of global traffic, largely lost in the noise of large-scale analyses, remote rural networks are the physical frontier of the Internet today. Through tight integration with a local operator’s infrastructure, we gather a unique dataset to characterize and report a year of interaction between finances, utilization, and performance of a novel, remote, data-only Community LTE Network in Bokondini, Indonesia. With visibility to drill down to individual users, we find use highly unbalanced and the network supported by only a handful of relatively heavy consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Cherry Jubilee Cake</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/chocolate-cherry-jubilee-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/chocolate-cherry-jubilee-cake/</guid>
      <description>My mom has been making this recipe for my family for as long as I can remember. It&amp;rsquo;s my sister&amp;rsquo;s favorite birthday cake, and probably mine as well! It&amp;rsquo;s especially good cold in a glass of milk&amp;hellip;
Instructions  Preheat the oven to 350F Grease and flour the pan Mix cake ingredients together in a large bowl Beat 2 minutes after combined at high speed Pour into the pan Bake until a toothpick inserted into the middle comes out clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking network congestion (Especially in community networks)</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/posts/rethinking-congestion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/posts/rethinking-congestion/</guid>
      <description>What is congestion in a network anyway? A network link suffers from congestion when demand for the link’s resources exceeds the amount of service it can supply within some reasonable duration of time, resulting in data being dropped on the floor or delayed. Both the “resources” and “reasonable duration of time” are highly situational and vary by application and type of network.[^1] Ultimately this becomes “ugh, why is the WiFi so slow today!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach, Mushroom, and Pesto Lasagna</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/pesto-lasagna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/pesto-lasagna/</guid>
      <description>Some of us have unfortunate allergies that make a typical lasagna an itchy and uncomfortable affair. I originally got this recipe from my partner&amp;rsquo;s mom, who found it online and modified it to taste. Give it a try and enjoy!
Instructions  Preheat the oven to 350f Grease a 9x13 baking pan Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Once heated, add the mushrooms, as well as salt and pepper to taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super easy black bean burgers</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/easy-black-bean-burgers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/easy-black-bean-burgers/</guid>
      <description>My partner and I found this recipe in an old college cookbook, and then heavily modified it to remove nightshades while still keeping a rich flavor! This is one of our newer favorite recipes and will probably evolve over time.
Instructions  Mash the beans, but not too much (use a food processor, blender, or just a fork). Add the onion, corn, salt, garlic powder, cilantro, and rosemary. Combine all ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Bean Dip</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/black-bean-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/black-bean-dip/</guid>
      <description>This recipe comes by way of my aunt Marilee. It was a crowd favorite growing up, and is absolutely amazing by the water on a hot sunny day!
Instructions  Combine marinade ingredients in a shaker bottle Shake&amp;hellip; shake&amp;hellip; shake&amp;hellip; yeaaaha! Pour marinade over beans and corn in a big bowl Let sit in fridge for 3 hours minimum, overnight if possible Drain marinade Add green onion and feta cheese Serve with fritos and/or scoop chips of choice!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tahini (Sesame) Free Garlic Hummus</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/hummus-no-tahini/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/hummus-no-tahini/</guid>
      <description>0: Gather Ingredients:  1 can of chickpeas 2 tbsp. of water 2 tablespoons of olive oil 1 good squeeze (1 tablespoon) of lemon juice 1 garlic clove 3/4 tsp. cumin 1/4 tsp. salt A few basil leaves if desired  1: Blend until creamy:  Add water (up to 2 additional tbsp.) as needed for consistency  Enjoy!  Refrigerate for storage, good for a few days :)   Licensed under CC BY-NC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Lives Matter</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/posts/blm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/posts/blm/</guid>
      <description>The fight to end systemic racism, particularly against my Black neighbors in the United States (my home), continues beyond the summer of 2020, beyond the 2020 election, and beyond a blog post. The Internet is a vast place, but in this corner I hope to make this undeniably clear. The injustice served to Breonna Taylor and Ahmaud Arbery this spring, to the many hundreds killed, and to millions of Black folks marginalized through systemic denial of opportunity in a country they helped build, is shameful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Lemon Bars</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/lemon-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/lemon-bars/</guid>
      <description>Originally born from two recipes. The first, based on a slight modification to a filling from a major baking website. The second, for the crust, recited from memory over a phone call and hurriedly written down before again forgotten!
Instructions  Preheat oven to 350F. Line a glass 9x13 pan with parchment paper Mix crust wet ingredients together Add flour for the crust and combine Press into the baking pan Bake 17 minutes  While crust is baking&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grandma Lonergan&#39;s Banana Bread</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>True origins unknown, but refined over many generations, this recipe makes a delicious soft banana bread. For maximum enjoyment be sure to not over-cook it, avoid over-mixing once you&amp;rsquo;ve combined the dry and wet ingredients, and consider adding some dark chocolate chips or favorite chopped nuts!
0: Prework:  Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan  1: In a large bowl mix:  2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt  2: In a separate bowl mix:  1 ½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) ¾ cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 2 T vanilla (that is not a typo&amp;hellip; two tablespoons is correct)  3: Put it all together:  Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ma&#39; Johnson&#39;s Fresh Blueberry Pie</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/blueberry-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/blueberry-pie/</guid>
      <description>Adapted and customized from a recipe appearing in a 1940&amp;rsquo;s cookbook, this recipe really hits the spot during summer fresh blueberry season.
You can make it as a traditional pie with a top crust, but the real magic is when you replace the top crust with the optional streusel topping detailed below.
Pie Instructions  Preheat oven to 425F. Prepare pie crust. In large bowl, combine blueberries, sugar, flour and cinnamon; toss lightly to mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve re-worked a lot of my own personal infrastructure, and learned a lot along the way. My ultimate goal will be to get all my infrastructure off of feed-based social media platforms and see how hard it is to recapture some of the magic of the young web, but of course that&amp;rsquo;s a long road ahead :)
I&amp;rsquo;m excited today to have finally finished one step on that journey, modernizing my old manual site onto a framework built around markdown content and a static site generator (I went with Hugo since I have some golang experience, I&amp;rsquo;m a little afraid of node_modules, and of course it&amp;rsquo;s fast).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiences: Design, Implementation, and Deployment of CoLTE, a Community LTE Solution</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/mobicom19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/mobicom19/</guid>
      <description>abstract: In this paper we introduce CoLTE, a solution for LTE-based community networks. CoLTE is a lightweight, Internet-only LTE core network (EPC) designed to facilitate the deployment and operation of small-scale, community owned and operated LTE networks in rural areas with limited and unreliable backhaul. The key differentiator of CoLTE, when compared to existing LTE solutions, is that in CoLTE the EPC is designed to be located in the field and deployed alongside a small number of cellular radios (eNodeBs), as opposed to the centralized model seen in large-scale telecom networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling community cellular networks with community cellular manager</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/nsdi19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/nsdi19/</guid>
      <description>abstract: Hundreds of millions of people still live beyond the coverage of basic mobile connectivity, primarily in rural areas with low population density. Mobile-network operators (MNOs) traditionally struggle to justify expansion into these rural areas due to the high infrastructure costs necessary to provide service. Community cellular networks, networks built &amp;ldquo;by and for&amp;rdquo; the people they serve, represent an alternative model that, to an extent, bypasses these business case limitations and enables sustainable rural coverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dLTE: Building a more WiFi-like Cellular Network: (Instead of the Other Way Around)</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/hotnets2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/hotnets2018/</guid>
      <description>abstract: The radio interfaces and network architectures of WiFi and cellular systems are converging along many dimensions. While both systems are largely adopting the centralized architecture of traditional cellular deployments, this design comes with fundamental disadvantages that limit how these networks grow and develop. As a response, we present Distributed LTE (dLTE), an architecture offering the high radio performance of licensed and coordinated waveforms as well as the openness to organic expansion and growth of traditional WiFi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowdsourcing Rural Network Maintenance and Repair via Network Messaging</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/chi2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/chi2018/</guid>
      <description>abstract: Repair and maintenance requirements limit the successful operation of rural infrastructure. Current best practices are centralized management, which requires travel from urban areas and is prohibitively expensive, or intensively training community members, which limits scaling. We explore an alternative model: crowdsourcing repair from the community. Leveraging a Community Cellular Network in the remote Philippines, we sent SMS to all active network subscribers (n = 63) requesting technical support. From the pool of physical respondents, we explored their ability to repair through mock failures and conducted semi-structured interviews about their experiences with repair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unplanned Obsolescence: Hardware and Software After Collapse</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/limits2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/limits2017/</guid>
      <description>abstract: In a setting of economic and infrastructural collapse, the inability to manufacture and maintain computing resources will be an enormous limitation on the continued use of technology. The concept of &amp;ldquo;rot&amp;rdquo; exists for both hardware and software, referring to a slow loss of functionality over time. Given a desire to maintain technological capability, we raise a variety of questions about technology use in such a scenario. How long will current hardware last through repair, robust construction, and good maintenance practices?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust and Technology Repair Infrastructures in the Remote Rural Philippines: Navigating Urban-Rural Seams</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/cscw2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/cscw2019/</guid>
      <description>abstract: This paper analyzes the processes and challenges of technology repair in remote, low-income areas far from standard ICT repair infrastructure. Our sites of study are the fishing and farming villages of Dibut, Diotorin, and Dikapinisan in Aurora Province, Philippines, located in coastal coves against a mountain range. Residents are geographically isolated from urban areas, with the nearest peri-urban center of Baler a boat trip of several hours away, infeasible in some sea conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
