<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cellular on matt9j:Matt Johnson</title>
    <link>https://matt9j.net/categories/cellular/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cellular on matt9j:Matt Johnson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matt9j.net/categories/cellular/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Asyncronous iperf3 Tests in Android 11&#43;</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/posts/integrating-iperf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/posts/integrating-iperf/</guid>
      <description>Preamble I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping out the Seattle Community Network (SCN), with an ongoing project to build a crowdsourced network performance measurement application for Android. While understanding modern network performance, particularly wireless networks, is extremely subtle, &amp;ldquo;speedtests&amp;rdquo; offer a crude yet popular way to measure a network&amp;rsquo;s performance, and are easy for general audiences to interpret.
Unsurprisingly, SCN sought to include a &amp;ldquo;speedtest&amp;rdquo; capability in their app! A team of volunteer undergraduate researchers (Zhennan(John) Zhou &amp;amp; Ashwin Chintalapati) organized by Esther Jang got started on the project, and started integrating iperf3 (C, BSD-3 into the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking network congestion (Especially in community networks)</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/posts/rethinking-congestion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/posts/rethinking-congestion/</guid>
      <description>What is congestion in a network anyway? A network link suffers from congestion when demand for the link’s resources exceeds the amount of service it can supply within some reasonable duration of time, resulting in data being dropped on the floor or delayed. Both the “resources” and “reasonable duration of time” are highly situational and vary by application and type of network.[^1] Ultimately this becomes “ugh, why is the WiFi so slow today!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling community cellular networks with community cellular manager</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/nsdi19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/nsdi19/</guid>
      <description>abstract: Hundreds of millions of people still live beyond the coverage of basic mobile connectivity, primarily in rural areas with low population density. Mobile-network operators (MNOs) traditionally struggle to justify expansion into these rural areas due to the high infrastructure costs necessary to provide service. Community cellular networks, networks built &amp;ldquo;by and for&amp;rdquo; the people they serve, represent an alternative model that, to an extent, bypasses these business case limitations and enables sustainable rural coverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dLTE: Building a more WiFi-like Cellular Network: (Instead of the Other Way Around)</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/hotnets2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/hotnets2018/</guid>
      <description>abstract: The radio interfaces and network architectures of WiFi and cellular systems are converging along many dimensions. While both systems are largely adopting the centralized architecture of traditional cellular deployments, this design comes with fundamental disadvantages that limit how these networks grow and develop. As a response, we present Distributed LTE (dLTE), an architecture offering the high radio performance of licensed and coordinated waveforms as well as the openness to organic expansion and growth of traditional WiFi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowdsourcing Rural Network Maintenance and Repair via Network Messaging</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/publications/chi2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/publications/chi2018/</guid>
      <description>abstract: Repair and maintenance requirements limit the successful operation of rural infrastructure. Current best practices are centralized management, which requires travel from urban areas and is prohibitively expensive, or intensively training community members, which limits scaling. We explore an alternative model: crowdsourcing repair from the community. Leveraging a Community Cellular Network in the remote Philippines, we sent SMS to all active network subscribers (n = 63) requesting technical support. From the pool of physical respondents, we explored their ability to repair through mock failures and conducted semi-structured interviews about their experiences with repair.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
