<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recipe on matt9j:Matt Johnson</title>
    <link>https://matt9j.net/tags/recipe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recipe on matt9j:Matt Johnson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matt9j.net/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Green Bean Casserole</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/green-bean-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/green-bean-casserole/</guid>
      <description>I love green bean casserole, a lot. Unfortunatley most &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; recipes require the use of canned condensed mushroom soup, which almost always has soy! I discovered this recipe for a version based on cheese instead, and have enjoyed it!
Instructions  Preheat the oven to 350F Melt butter into a large skillet (medium heat) Add flower and stir until it forms a smooth paste Quickly add green beans, sour cream, salt, and sugar&amp;ndash; don&amp;rsquo;t let the flower paste get overcooked/burned!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Cherry Jubilee Cake</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/chocolate-cherry-jubilee-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/chocolate-cherry-jubilee-cake/</guid>
      <description>My mom has been making this recipe for my family for as long as I can remember. It&amp;rsquo;s my sister&amp;rsquo;s favorite birthday cake, and probably mine as well! It&amp;rsquo;s especially good cold in a glass of milk&amp;hellip;
Instructions  Preheat the oven to 350F Grease and flour the pan Mix cake ingredients together in a large bowl Beat 2 minutes after combined at high speed Pour into the pan Bake until a toothpick inserted into the middle comes out clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach, Mushroom, and Pesto Lasagna</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/pesto-lasagna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/pesto-lasagna/</guid>
      <description>Some of us have unfortunate allergies that make a typical lasagna an itchy and uncomfortable affair. I originally got this recipe from my partner&amp;rsquo;s mom, who found it online and modified it to taste. Give it a try and enjoy!
Instructions  Preheat the oven to 350f Grease a 9x13 baking pan Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Once heated, add the mushrooms, as well as salt and pepper to taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super easy black bean burgers</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/easy-black-bean-burgers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/easy-black-bean-burgers/</guid>
      <description>My partner and I found this recipe in an old college cookbook, and then heavily modified it to remove nightshades while still keeping a rich flavor! This is one of our newer favorite recipes and will probably evolve over time.
Instructions  Mash the beans, but not too much (use a food processor, blender, or just a fork). Add the onion, corn, salt, garlic powder, cilantro, and rosemary. Combine all ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Bean Dip</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/black-bean-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/black-bean-dip/</guid>
      <description>This recipe comes by way of my aunt Marilee. It was a crowd favorite growing up, and is absolutely amazing by the water on a hot sunny day!
Instructions  Combine marinade ingredients in a shaker bottle Shake&amp;hellip; shake&amp;hellip; shake&amp;hellip; yeaaaha! Pour marinade over beans and corn in a big bowl Let sit in fridge for 3 hours minimum, overnight if possible Drain marinade Add green onion and feta cheese Serve with fritos and/or scoop chips of choice!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tahini (Sesame) Free Garlic Hummus</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/hummus-no-tahini/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/hummus-no-tahini/</guid>
      <description>0: Gather Ingredients:  1 can of chickpeas 2 tbsp. of water 2 tablespoons of olive oil 1 good squeeze (1 tablespoon) of lemon juice 1 garlic clove 3/4 tsp. cumin 1/4 tsp. salt A few basil leaves if desired  1: Blend until creamy:  Add water (up to 2 additional tbsp.) as needed for consistency  Enjoy!  Refrigerate for storage, good for a few days :)   Licensed under CC BY-NC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Lemon Bars</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/lemon-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/lemon-bars/</guid>
      <description>Originally born from two recipes. The first, based on a slight modification to a filling from a major baking website. The second, for the crust, recited from memory over a phone call and hurriedly written down before again forgotten!
Instructions  Preheat oven to 350F. Line a glass 9x13 pan with parchment paper Mix crust wet ingredients together Add flour for the crust and combine Press into the baking pan Bake 17 minutes  While crust is baking&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grandma Lonergan&#39;s Banana Bread</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>True origins unknown, but refined over many generations, this recipe makes a delicious soft banana bread. For maximum enjoyment be sure to not over-cook it, avoid over-mixing once you&amp;rsquo;ve combined the dry and wet ingredients, and consider adding some dark chocolate chips or favorite chopped nuts!
0: Prework:  Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan  1: In a large bowl mix:  2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt  2: In a separate bowl mix:  1 ½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) ¾ cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 2 T vanilla (that is not a typo&amp;hellip; two tablespoons is correct)  3: Put it all together:  Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ma&#39; Johnson&#39;s Fresh Blueberry Pie</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/blueberry-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/blueberry-pie/</guid>
      <description>Adapted and customized from a recipe appearing in a 1940&amp;rsquo;s cookbook, this recipe really hits the spot during summer fresh blueberry season.
You can make it as a traditional pie with a top crust, but the real magic is when you replace the top crust with the optional streusel topping detailed below.
Pie Instructions  Preheat oven to 425F. Prepare pie crust. In large bowl, combine blueberries, sugar, flour and cinnamon; toss lightly to mix.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
