<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recipes on matt9j:Matt Johnson</title>
    <link>https://matt9j.net/categories/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recipes on matt9j:Matt Johnson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matt9j.net/categories/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tahini (Sesame) Free Garlic Hummus</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/hummus-no-tahini/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/hummus-no-tahini/</guid>
      <description>0: Gather Ingredients:  1 can of chickpeas 2 tbsp. of water 2 tablespoons of olive oil 1 good squeeze (1 tablespoon) of lemon juice 1 garlic clove 3/4 tsp. cumin 1/4 tsp. salt A few basil leaves if desired  1: Blend until creamy:  Add water (up to 2 additional tbsp.) as needed for consistency  Enjoy!  Refrigerate for storage, good for a few days :)   Licensed under CC BY-NC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Lemon Bars</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/lemon-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/lemon-bars/</guid>
      <description>Originally born from two recipes. The first, based on a slight modification to a filling from a major baking website. The second, for the crust, recited from memory over a phone call and hurriedly written down before again forgotten!
Instructions  Preheat oven to 350F. Line a glass 9x13 pan with parchment paper Mix crust wet ingredients together Add flour for the crust and combine Press into the baking pan Bake 17 minutes  While crust is baking&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grandma Lonergan&#39;s Banana Bread</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>True origins unknown, but refined over many generations, this recipe makes a delicious soft banana bread. For maximum enjoyment be sure to not over-cook it, avoid over-mixing once you&amp;rsquo;ve combined the dry and wet ingredients, and consider adding some dark chocolate chips or favorite chopped nuts!
0: Prework:  Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan  1: In a large bowl mix:  2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt  2: In a separate bowl mix:  1 ½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) ¾ cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 2 T vanilla (that is not a typo&amp;hellip; two tablespoons is correct)  3: Put it all together:  Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ma&#39; Johnson&#39;s Fresh Blueberry Pie</title>
      <link>https://matt9j.net/recipes/blueberry-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matt9j.net/recipes/blueberry-pie/</guid>
      <description>Adapted and customized from a recipe appearing in a 1940&amp;rsquo;s cookbook, this recipe really hits the spot during summer fresh blueberry season.
You can make it as a traditional pie with a top crust, but the real magic is when you replace the top crust with the optional streusel topping detailed below.
Pie Instructions  Preheat oven to 425F. Prepare pie crust. In large bowl, combine blueberries, sugar, flour and cinnamon; toss lightly to mix.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
